Andrii Skliar

SENIOR RESEARCH ENGINEER @ QUALCOMM AI RESEARCH

Amsterdam, Netherlands

■ andrew.skliar@gmail.com | 🖸 github.com/askliar | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/andriiskliar | 📚 Andrii Skliar

Personal Profile

Al Research Engineer with a foundation in software engineering and over 5 years of in-depth research. Co-author of multiple influential publications, with main focus on model efficiency. My expertise lies in optimizing model performance while ensuring resource effectiveness, bridging academic theory and real-world practicality.

Work Experience

Oualcomm AI Research

Amsterdam, Netherlands

Senior Research Engineer

Oct 2019 - Currently

- Worked on model efficiency within research team formerly lead by Prof. Max Welling., where I led hardware-oriented ML projects and notably
 contributed to the DONNA Neural Architecture Search Algorithm, integrated into Qualcomm's AIMET library, as well as simulated quantization
 project resulting in a 17% energy reduction on Qualcomm hardware without compromising accuracy.
- Supported research on model efficiency topics, from Neural Architecture Search to Efficient Mixture-of-Experts, leading to a range of successful publications.

QUVA LabAmsterdam, Netherlands

Research Intern May 2019 – Oct 2019

- Master's thesis internship in collaboration with QUVA Lab under the supervision of Maurice Weiler.
- Extended theory of Hyperbolic Neural Networks to Convolutional and Graph Neural Networks.

Intetics Inc. Kyiv, Ukraine

Software Engineer Feb 2017 - Aug 2017

• Technology stack: Haskell, MySQL, Python, PHP

Education

University of Amsterdam, Netherlands

MSc in Artificial Intelligence

Sep 2017 - Aug 2019

- GPA: 8.8/10, Cum Laude
- Honours programme with multiple successful research projects.
- · Courses in Theoretical and Applied Machine Learning

NTUU "Kyiv Polytechnical University" ESC "Insitute of Applied System Analysis"

Kyiv, Ukraine

BSc in System Analysis

Sep 2013 - Jul 2017

- GPA: 4.74/5, Top 5% of the Year Group

Publications

Hyperbolic Convolutional Neural Networks

Andrii Skliar, Maurice Weiler

2023

Simulated quantization, real power savings

Mart Baalen, Brian Kahne, Eric Mahurin, Andrey Kuzmin, Andrii Skliar, Markus Nagel, Tijmen Blankevoort

Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2022

$Simple\ and\ Efficient\ Architectures\ for\ Semantic\ Segmentation$

Dushyant Mehta, Andrii Skliar, Haitam Ben Yahia, Shubhankar Borse, Fatih Porikli, Amirhossein Habibian, Tijmen Blankevoort Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2022

Revisiting single-gated Mixtures of Experts

Amelie Royer, Ilia Karmanov, Andrii Skliar, Babak Ehteshami Bejnordi, Tijmen Blankevoort

33rd British Machine Vision Conference 2022, BMVC 2022, London, UK, November 21-24, 2022, 2022

Cyclical pruning for sparse neural networks

Suraj Srinivas, Andrey Kuzmin, Markus Nagel, Mart Baalen, Andrii Skliar, Tijmen Blankevoort

Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2022

Distilling optimal neural networks: Rapid search in diverse spaces

Bert Moons, Parham Noorzad, Andrii Skliar, Giovanni Mariani, Dushyant Mehta, Chris Lott, Tijmen Blankevoort Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision, 2021

Adding object detection skills to visual dialogue agents

Gabriele Bani, Davide Belli, Gautier Dagan, Alexander Geenen, Andrii Skliar, Aashish Venkatesh, Tim Baumgartner, Elia Bruni, Raquel

Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) Workshops, 2018

August 31, 2023